This call is 2 is about how to make
entries in into ABC metadata tables.
OK.
I just think it's my voice.
Yeah, yeah.
And recordings of the starting drift.
Yeah, yeah.
So first one is match metadata table.
So in this in this table we'll make
entries into.
We'll make entries at the batch level.
OK let me run this.
So batch ID will be a automated
incremented begin value and we like while
making the entry DML entry.
We don't need to specify this value.
It will be auto increment batch name.
Batch name should have a structure like
if it is zone 2,
it should be Z2_bash_source_domain name.
So currently we have this ABC framework
first source single source to single
domain load, source source to domain load.
So the batch name convention as of now is
this.
But in case if we have any update in the
standard format for this value,
we'll notify you, OK.
And batch description should be something
like this.
Batch to load data from CMPM is the
source 2,
Broker is the broker is the domain.
So data domain is the layer within the
zone 2.
So in zone 2, we have two zone 2 layers,
right Data domain and functional.
So this match is related to CMPM source
to broker data domain load.
So description should be like this and is
active field is just two.
I like indicate the active entry e-mail
ID here.
As of now we are we are keeping our mail
ID.
In future we will keep the like e-mail ID.
I think we will get it in future.
For now we can keep it for like we can
keep our entry,
our mail ID here and source name should
be our June month source name.
Like if you also overseas June 1 then you
have to keep your phone one source name
then domain name is rocker.
Application name can be null.
Like we're as of now we are not using
this column so it can be null.
Application layer name would be data
domain.
So in June 2 we have two layers right?
Data domain functional.
If you are loading to data domain then it
can be data domain otherwise it will be
functional.
My application dependency name this
particular batch what is dependent on
CMPM batch look so that's why we have.
I have given this here and we have to
provide the corresponding CMPMS batch ID
here as application source batch ID and
target zone.
It will be either zone 2 or zone 3 and
low frequency depend again it depends on
your batch.
If your batch is intended intended to be
lowered daily, then it it should be daily.
If it is weekly or monthly it it it has
to be like weekly or monthly scheduling
mechanism.
As of now scheduler we have a stone
branch.
Will you rate We have got this and load
schedule time,
load expectation expected completion time.
These details will be actual values will
be populated once we started creating the
jobs in the stone branch and once we get
the actual schedule times and expected.
For now I have made some dummy entries.
So this has to be updated once the stone
batch jobs are created for our batch to
trigger audit create date time,
audit update date time or just current
timestamp value columns.
You can use CURRENT our time stamp
function in our already way to populate
this and order created by user ID,
audit updated by user ID or also just
current user you can use your You can use
your mail ID here.
Otherwise you can also use current user
function but it is giving some token
number as username that is fine like
whatever you are making here.
But we we can update it later like if any
standard format is there.
OK,
kiosks column is it is related to June 1
specific column.
OK,
is everyone good here or can I move on to
the next or just one thing?
So source name and your application
source name would be the same one.
Yeah,
because source we are expecting one
source and password right And then job.
So here the source is CMPM and
application source name is also CMPM.
So is it like yeah in both we are
populating the source values like source
name values.
So this proper domain whatever the load
is just dependent on CMPM.
So if we have any other you know any
other application any other domain load
which is depend which is loading from
zone 1 but it's load is dependent on
another zone 2 batch then we can add it.
We can add that particular batch also.
Here as of now we have only one source so
and this particular application doesn't
have dependency on any other application.
So we have kept only CMPM.
But in future,
if we have multiple sources or if we have
dependency on any other June 2 batch also
we have to include the corresponding
dependency names here.
So if separated batch has multiple
dependencies,
let's say it has multiple sources.
So then we'll have multiple entries over
here like we haven't like discussed or
have the design for multiple sources for
APC as of now.
But like we plan to discuss on the design
on multiple sources to single domain load
whenever the scenario or any source
system have that particular requirement.
As of now, we don't have that.
OK, for now,
it's just that application dependency
name is the source name.
So because one source, one matcher,
it will be that.
Yeah, yeah.
And also not only source,
but also if we have any equivalent June.
So if we if my broker domain load is
dependent on any other brand,
any other batch of June 2 also that can
also be included here.
But anyway the logic is not supporting
currently.
Like we are considering a single source
and single dependency.
OK and application source batch ID is the
zone 1 batch ID right?
Like the zone 1 whatever,
whatever application name that we have
given here, Yeah,
corresponding batch ID should be.
And while we are retrieving like while we
are making entry,
we are using source name, source name,
domain name,
application layer name and target job.
We are using these 4 columns to fetch the
batch ID corresponding batch area to make
entries into job run stage table.
OK, we're good right?
OK,
let's move on to the job metric data
table.
So geometry data table here we'll make
entries at job level with it like 1 batch
will have multiple jobs.
So here I'm just taking one table load as
a as a job.
So here job ID is also again it's a
incremented value,
auto increment value job name.
It's it is having a structure similar to
batch name.
It should have Z2 as we as this table
load is happening in June 2,
we have given Z2_job_CMPM,
IS the source name broker,
is the domain name and broker party
address is the table name and then load
so.
This is the standard format that that we
have to follow for our job name and this
is not the final one we Need to discuss
about batch name and job name with
netwika If.
We have any changes in this in this
format, we will we will notify.
OK, let's move on to this next one.
Job description.
It is also a job to load broker party
address is the table name from CMP miss
the source name in broker is the domain
name and data domain is the application
layer name.
It has to be like this job to load table
name from source name in domain name data
domain.
This is the application layer is active
indicators to use two indicate the active
entry and batch ID is the corresponding
batch ID.
So whatever the batch that we have for
broker domain, CMPM to broker domain,
so the corresponding batch ID should be
kept here and then table name,
table name and this is the target table
name,
whatever the target that we are that we
are trying to load using using this job
and scheme learning database name,
job load type, task flow.
So the workflow name and wrapper workflow
name is in the sense like we'll have a
task flow at the job level that is one
translate at the job level.
And on top of that,
we'll have a another task flow which is
batch translow which is nothing but the
wrapper workflow name.
OK,
these workflow names have the standard
like, right?
It has already shared the format that
needs to be followed for IACS components,
right?
Yeah, yeah.
So there we have task flow.
So it should be like this task T
TSKFL_load target domain so.
Stable name two targetable this.
Has to be like this task flow name OK IF
it is batch so.
I CAN start preparing the TDs For those
tables right if?
It is batch task flow it,
should follow this TSKFL load target
domain source,
domain to target zone target application
layer batch so.
This has to be like this task flow load
draw curve, zone 1-2, zone two,
data domain batch OK and count threshold
indicator.
In the sense if we have any balance
reconciliation metric wherein we are
trying to do a count count check then we
have to like make this indicator as we
else it can be ends.
For amount balance check indicator.
This is all the same if we have any
amount columns that needs to be validated
validated with the like among the source
between the source and target then it has
to be by else it can be N auditory data.
These four are just normal columns.
K Rs is just related to John one specific
column.
Target to John layer should be like
refined to John two data domains.
So for this particular broker,
target to source to target layer is
refined to zone to data domain.
It's just like source layer to target
layer.
Whatever the layers that from which we
are give,
we are taking the data from to target
layer.
Target layer is zone to data domain for
this particular broker.
Yeah.
Does anyone have any questions?
Yes.
People have the tabs here.
Hello.
OK, Sir.
Hello.
Yeah, sure does it.
Yes.
OK.
Can we move on to the next one?
This is config load.
This particular table is related to you
know like which will it is.
It is just like a batch grid requisite
for our actual batch,
our flow we'll check whether the source
batch is completed or whether our source
batch is in now completed or partial
state like that.
And also so there is a batch prerequisite
wherein we'll check our whether our batch
current batch task flow is completed
successfully or not.
If it is completed successfully then like
previous run,
if it is completed successfully then we
are going to check whether our source
batch within the given time window like
within the given time if it is completed
or not.
So this way we will like if this if we
have the source batch like expected
source batch which is in completed to
partial state then we are go to starter
don't do batch.
So for that check like readiness we are
using this table.
So this is having target batch ID,
source batch ID, source name, domain name.
So target batch ID in the sense like our
broker data domain batch ID,
source batch ID, CMPM batch ID,
source name is CMPM domain name is broker.
It's just like a mandatory time check is
nothing but a active entry and dependency
batch time stamp.
So here it's like a cut off time.
So it's like if for for example,
for CMPM 2,
for CMPM load in June or for CMPM,
let's say if we have 4 batches in a day
and one batch for broker in June 2,
we are planning to load our broker table
once.
Once the 4th batch run or final batch run
in a day of June 1 CMPM gets completed.
OK,
let's say this CMPM June 1 batch gets
completed at 12:00 AM in the morning,
12:00 AM in the morning.
Then my batch batch start time stamp,
dependency batch time stamp will be like
12:00 PM.
So every day before starting my broker
batch, let's say my broker batch,
I have scheduled it one PM 1:00 AM.
So my zone 2 batch is scheduled at 12:00
AM.
So my dependency batch is having 12,
right?
So at every every day we will check
whether the batch with the batch start
time with the current,
we will we'll concatenate the current
date value with this and we will check if
the 4th like 12 AM batch is either in
completed or partial state.
So if it is completed or partial state
then we are good to go.
We we are good to start the June 2 batch.
OK so for this only we are having a POC
going on to check whether the stone
branch is able to take the ISES status or
not.
So if the stone branch would be able to
trigger once this like prerequisite batch
gets successfully completed then it
whether it would be able to trigger the
next batch.
If the prerequisite is failed due to due
to any reason,
it should not trigger the actual batch
transfer.
OK this is related to the batch
prerequisite.
OK the last four gesture audit columns.
The main thing is the we are getting here
is this batch cut off time dependency
batch start there OK hello.
If we are good on this,
we can move on to the next multi trip.
OK,
let's move on to this ETL data ingestion
metadata table.
So this table is user for it.
It acts like a metadata for ETL ingestion
sourcing window.
So for incremental load like this table,
using this table we will create a
sourcing window entry in the ETL
ingestion sourcing window table.
So that from there we will pick the
sourcing dates and we will fetch the
incremental data.
So this is the metadata for it.
It it is containing target batch ID which
is nothing but the broker batch ID.
In this case,
target job ID is the our table loads job
ID to state and then target table name is
broker party address, source name is CMPM,
source table name is ADW.
Whatever the source name from which we
are taking, if we have multiple sources,
we can add multiple entries here.
Multiple source tables.
Sorry, multiple source tables.
We can add multiple entries here.
OK,
so if these tables are currently our ABC
framework will hold.
Will work fine if we have multiple source
tables that are loading under a single
source batch.
So if I if I have multiple table entries
which are coming from the same source,
then I can make multiple entries.
So for every corresponding table,
the corresponding table of corresponding
sourcing stardom and sourcing entom will
be pull from will be pulled and used here
because John when is currently updating,
it's just like a no like June 1 in June 1.
How the June 1 batch hacks like if any
one of the table get is loaded completely
successfully and others have failed,
they're marking the status as partial.
If all the tables in the batch get
successfully completed,
then then they are making it as completed.
So if any one of the job gets failed in
the June 1,
so then also they're making it as a
partial entry based upon the job end time
and jobs load status where we are
creating a sourcing window for the
particular table.
Instead of taking directly like standard
source,
like single sourcing window for the
entire entire batch,
we are taking it at the source job level.
OK, so it should have like for this table,
let's say ETL data, initial metadata,
right?
Basically if one batch has multiple
source tables,
it will have multiple entries and
sourcing and start and end time
accordingly.
Is that the correct time is coming?
Yeah.
If, if for example,
if broker party address is my source
target table,
it is having dependency on ADW party
address T and it is also getting data
from ADW party T OK,
so then I'll have two entries and based
upon their particular load status in the
zone 1.
So all these job statuses and job end
time will be available in the job run
stats table.
OK.
We'll get the job end time and status
from there and we will a populate
sourcing startum and sourcing and and the
runtime table.
So from there we can keep,
we can pick the sourcing startum and
sourcing entry during the load.
So that will be picked for the job
preload as part of job preload there
which and that will be taken care, right?
Yeah, yeah, job preload,
it will be taken care.
So,
so basically we will be using this table
using these two parameters.
I I will get the source table name and
target table name using source table name
and source batch source batch ID.
We'll also get the source batch ID from
the batch metadata table.
So using into these two values,
we will be looking up on the job metadata
and getting the job IDs.
Using those job IDs we'll get the status
and job and name.
So all this logic will be already in is
already in place in the gym ETL data
initiation sourcing window table.
So it's already there.
OK.
And then next moving on to the job role
master.
We are good here, right everyone sorry,
ITL data initiation.
OK, let's move on to the job role master.
Job role master it's it's it's like a it
it it's like it.
It holds all the list of DQ checks.
It's not at batch level or job level.
It's a it it contains different list of
all the checks that needs to be performed
across all jobs or all all jobs,
all jobs and across all batches and jobs.
OK so here rule ID will be an auto
incremented value Rule name is For now I
have this consider null check and its
scope is at the column level and audit
this folder just audit columns that's it
rule name and rule scope.
If you have any date format check then
also we can we have to add first entry
here then we can use this particular rule
in our batch or job.
OK,
similarly like not only date format not
check if we have any other like you check
like length check whatever we can see we
have to 1st add the true here and then
only we can use it in the next we can
assign that particular rule to our job.
OK,
this is the job rule assignment table
where we'll assign the rules to our jobs.
OK, job rule assignment ID,
it's an auto incremental value.
Next validation type,
we are performing the DQ check preload
only before loading the target table.
That's why we have given the value as pre
and whatever the target columns upon
which we are planning to perform this DQ
check,
we are giving them these pattern
available pattern available.
These two are related to zone one OK and
error severity code.
It is like it.
It can hold like critical or information,
OK, if we if they it's like if,
if any DQ check that needs to be like
that is very critical,
then we have to mark it as critical.
If it is just information we just need we
can load it like we can if any record has
any informational DQ check failure.
Like if if any error informational error
record is there then we can load that
particular record into target.
But we'll inform we load that particular
record into both target and error detail
tables and we inform the we inform admin
team regarding this informational error.
We'll notify them basically.
So here error text is as I'm doing a null
check.
I have just given null values found.
You can take any error error message
trick based upon your DQ is active as
chest active indicator or create data all
these portal audit columns and rule IDs.
So this is null check right?
And the rule master we have rule ID right
for for null check it's one.
So the that corresponding rule ID should
be kept here and the corresponding job ID
needs to be given here.
OK.
Here we have to provide the exact target
table, target column values, OK.
And then if we go down this,
we can move on to this balance
reconciliation metric.
So like if you have any balancing metrics
needs to be reconciled,
we'll make an entry into this table.
So here it's an auto incremented value
metric ID, balance check,
cancellation metric,
metric description is just like here I'm
trying to get a word extend count check
of this particular broker party
identifier.
And like I'm doing this a distinct count
check of this column between source and
target.
So that's what I have written here.
Here we have to do reconcile distinct
count of this column.
If we have any amount column,
we can directly write reconcile total
broker amount value from source June 1 to
like source June source to target John
target.
So it just like a reconcile listing count
of broker party address from zone,
one source to zone to target that's it.
Balancing type discount, if it is amount,
we can keep it as amount source to target
layer.
It's again just source layer to target
layer.
That's it refined to join to data domain,
target database name.
So target data this is just a target
database name,
target schema name and target table name.
OK, this is target column,
column name upon which we are trying to
perform reconciliation OK and region
source path,
these are related to John one.
OK, source query, target query.
As of now we don't need this.
We have already implemented logic
dynamically within the ETL itself.
Threshold type name is percentage.
We can have threshold type as percentage
or value.
So if it is percentage,
the calculation in the dynamic table like
in the dynamic logic would be different.
If it is valued directly,
it will check threshold type and the
threshold value.
We have to provide the threshold.
So if any metrics,
source and target metrics are out of
balance,
we will like compare against this
threshold value.
If it is within threshold,
then we like based upon if it is within
threshold or out of threshold,
we'll send out a message or update the
status in the job run starts so far that
we will use this column and either add to
indicator,
it's just add to indicator and then we
have to provide the job ID to date.
Yeah.
Are we good with the My Data tables?
Anyone have any questions here in the
metadata tables?
OK, I'll take it as no.
Let's move on.
OK, this is logged up.
Let me log on to yes.
Yes.
I'm just trying to give you a high level
overview of the ABC integration where the
components are like that.
I just I'm just trying to do so we have
different folders for different domains.
DAA common?
It's a folder where we are trying to keep
ABC and config driven like which like
whatever which is common for all the
domain loads we are trying to keep it
here.
We we are having all the ABC components
here.
But what I'll say is currently testing
for the one of the table in the one of
the tables in the broker domain is in
progress.
So I'm just making some changes in a
basic component there.
So what I'll what I'll recommend to you
to you guys to use is whatever the ABC
components which are present in the
broker folder.
Under every domain folder we again have
ABC main, MVP stage folder subfolders.
So all for every domain we will get the
copy.
Usually it has to be like whatever the
ABC components which are present in the
common folder should be copied into this
folder and then we have to use.
As of now as the testing is in progress,
I'm directly making the changes here.
Once.
If you want to use,
you can use the components from this
folder as of now.
But later I'll try to like make all the
components in the common folder sync with
the with this with these OK.
And after that under main folders,
I have created a task flow at the job
level.
OK,
so you don't need to do anything in the
ABC,
ABC components if you like if your domain
have similar structure as that of broker,
but for conflict driven we like we'll
have we don't have these many component
it it's somewhat simplified one we can
discuss it at the end.
OK, all the components will be here only.
You just need to create just like take a
reference of this just or otherwise take
a copy of this task flow and you can just
do what you have to do is if for this
particular data broker domain,
we have two hops within the same job.
One is from source to stage and the other
is from stage 2 actual main targeted
broker party address.
So here first we first in the start step,
we'll have input fields.
OK, let me open the batch task flow first.
It's it's the highest one Painful.
So this is the batch transfer which will
hold all the jobs of task flows.
OK.
So this is our but job subtask flow.
We have created this batch transfer with
only one job.
But like upon the orchestration design,
we can integrate all the job levels of
task flows based upon the orchestration
and front order.
OK, so first initially in the batch table,
I I just want to show you 3 points here.
So param file should be created as per
your domain.
OK.
And also DQ indicator is mandatory.
It has to be provide I'll show you sample
parameter file here.
So here we have DQ check indicator, right?
This has to be provided within the
parameter file.
Based upon this we have a logic in the in
the task flow whether to execute few task
flows which are related to this DQ
validation.
OK.
And in the common folder wherever we have
snowflake snowflake connection,
we have given as common ABC snowflake in
the common folder.
Once you copy them into your actual ABC
folder like domain level ABC folder,
you have to update the update this
connection like connection PGT and pure
domain.
This has to be this is the format.
So what usually all our targets will be
in Snowflake only, right?
So I'm just try like I'll who have a
single a connection name for a Snowflake
database as a standard we are just like
planning to have single connection across.
So you will find this connections ABC in
few mappings ETL data ingestion.
There are two components related to this
ETL data ingestion sourcing window table.
So there you will found job where a
detail you will found balance
reconciliation you'll found and postal
success.
So all these places in all these places
you will found this connection.
Just update the connection name in the
FPC component.
That's it.
OK.
And also one more.
OK,
let me tell you that whenever this comes,
OK, that's it.
And here in the batch level task flow
let's move on from the start step.
In the start step we have input fields.
Right here we have to provide the
parameter file, directory name,
static value and parameter file and also
you audit user ID.
We are using the service account like
which is triggering this job.
Just using this and build function of
IDMC OK.
And then I'm using some temporary fields
like error count and batch status,
which will be used it to track the job
failures.
And batch status is nothing.
But like based upon the error count,
we are just we're,
we're just getting the batch like we're
just assigning the batch status.
And we're using this batch status to
update the status in our batch
translation table, et cetera.
Next component is batch transfers preload
this,
this component just holds some mapping
test,
which will make an entry into our batch
transfers table.
I'm just making a error handling so that
if this task fails using the execution,
it will throw an error and it will also
fail the task flow.
So this is our actual batch,
our job level task flow.
I'll just go to this flow in a minute.
If this is failed like if any job failed,
I'm just using an assign assignment task
to update my error count.
So initially I have provided error count
as zero.
If any of the job gets failed it will be
incremented OK in the decision.
I'm using this error count.
So similarly if we have any other jobs
like once all the job loads are completed
then we we we will check for the error
count value.
If it is equals to 0 then we will assign
C to our batch status else it will be F
So based upon the status,
the status in the batch and batch enter
will be updated.
See here I'm using this time status as as
my as one parameter.
So using this it will be emulated OK if
this component fails,
it's just I'm just doing error handling.
It will just throw an error and it will
fail the task room.
OK yeah.
And also based upon the batch status,
I'm sending out the success notification
and failure notification.
If my batch is successful then it will
just goes to end.
If it is failed we will send out the
failure notification and we will fail the
task.
Are we good on the batch task flow?
So this is issue we have to can you just
once you can explain what are parameters
it is expecting from a parameter file for
as part of patch with manager preview.
OK,
So if you see here like whatever the
values that I have provided here in the
input fields,
it is expecting only those I can say here.
So ABC database name,
ABC schema name and source name,
domain name,
target zone source source join is not
required.
It is required for batch.
For that, OK, application layer name,
that's it.
These four,
these four application layer name,
target zone domain name, source name,
ABC database name, ABC schema name, OK.
This it is also expected.
I told you right,
We are just passing this service account
value to our audit user ID, OK?
Batch post load Also,
it's just getting the batch ID from the
batch preload and the status or you
choose ID from the formula and these two
will be from the parameter file.
OK, let's move on to this job level task.
So in the job level task flow we'll have
a job preload,
actual main load and job post load.
OK.
So we'll have all these job, task,
job reload, task flow,
whatever the task flow subtask flow that
I have given here for ABC,
all these 4 task flows will already
present in the ABC folder.
You would just need to pull that.
So in the start step,
we have to get the parameter file
directory, parameter file name, batch ID,
execution, run ID, batch name,
execution runtime source, batch ID,
source execution, run ID,
source end time and audit choose ready.
So if you go to this batch level task
flow,
let me show I have already assigned
whatever the input.
Input fields that are required in my task
flow are already provided here.
So you can refer to this task flow on how
to like get the parameters from which
component like mostly or from batch
transfers,
preload if you are from these three are
from input fields.
That's it.
You can refer to this particular batch
task flow while creating your domain
level, your domain's batch task flow.
OK,
so upon getting all these input parameter
files,
we we will use them in the downstream
components.
They're not time fields,
we're just choosing improvements.
And this is the ABC job preload.
So task to ABC job preload,
this is the task to that we have to use
for ABC.
So once you get the copy of all the ABC
components in the respect to in your
respect to domain level ABC folder,
you have to select that particular job
job preload component and you have to
assign the input input parameters.
So it is expecting batch ID execution run
ID, batch name execution run type source,
batch ID source execution run ID,
source batching time parameter,
file directory parameter file name audit
use rightly.
So these are the parameters that are
expected that are needed in job ABC job
reload OK and then if this task flow
fails during the execution and then this
will be triggered This is ABC job preload
failure.
So it it is expecting these parameters
that file parameter,
file directory parameter filing job run
ID, job ID,
batch name BQ check all these we will get
from them job preload only.
So if it's a job,
so whatever the parameter values that we
get from the parameter from the job run
sets,
we will we'll have those parameters and
we'll send out a notification.
OK, OK.
And then so the there is a situation like
there's a scenario like in case of free,
in case of free start of our batch,
if any of the tables load is already
completed,
then we should skip the table load.
So we'll get we'll have a skip flag from
the ABC job preload.
So if it is Y then we will skipping the
entire load.
We're just going to the end.
OK,
If it is a device then we'll go and load
OK like this.
Skip flag value will be settled in the
job record only.
OK this is the mapping task.
First source to stage load OK,
we have to just select our mapping task
and whatever the parameters that we are
required will be,
will be will be assigned here mostly as
part of ABC.
So we're implementing the ABC,
ABC like ABC related integration in the
source to stage load only.
And also we're using snowflake timetables
for this load in order to enable full PDO.
I'll just go on a minute about this task
flow stage level 2.
So otherwise I'll just open it to be over.
So here what I need is audit user ID,
execution run ID and job ID,
job run ID that's ABC related ABC,
Snowflake ABC database name,
Snowflake ABC schema name.
And so system go to an AB.
Yeah, we,
we are to use as we are using Snowflake
Temptables to populate ABC related
entries.
In order to enable full PDO,
we are using ABC,
a related database and scheme.
So we are already providing these two
values here,
Snowflake ABC database name and Snowflake
ABC scheme.
OK, let me open this.
I'll just cover whatever we have for ABC
integration.
So as of now for this blocker party,
we have implemented job run stats,
balance,
reconciliation and error handling DQ
checks.
So here in the expression transformation,
we have expression tab.
So here we have different column names.
All these are user for error,
error DQ checks.
OK, so this error description column,
we'll have a format like this.
So it's just checking.
So we have given 4 TQ checks for this
particular job right?
So if any one of this is null then it
will just concatenate its target column
value, source column value,
source source value and the rule ID and
critical CBR.
These two are hard coded OK like we have
to look into the job sorry job rule
master table and get this and we have to
get this from job rule SMP table.
These two are hard coded only OK if any
one of this is fail.
We are just making like we are just
creating an entry into this table into
this particular error description.
So for every record it will create one
entry into the like it will prepare 1
error description for all the DQ checks.
So if if my party ID so for a particular
record,
if I'm getting all these columns as null
then my error description will look like
this.
It will have this.
What will happens like this It will be so
it will have all the error DQ check
related information for each and updated
code.
OK error description will have we have
like this.
So in the error detail part it will just
like split using this;
And it will retrieve column source record
and column level information like it will
just transpose this particular record
into 4 records in the error detail.
So for each and every source record and
column level information will be there in
single record in in the actually BC job
role label.
It's a different logic.
I'm just like letting you know that this
error description is intended,
intended for that purpose.
OK, it is an is.
Is anyone having any question?
If we have only two,
then we'll have we'll have this.
We'll have only two if we have any like
for a particular for a incoming source
record.
If we have a nil value for only two
columns,
then our error description will look like
this.
OK,
this logic is already in place for rocker
party address.
You can just copy and use it for your
trip.
Is is everyone good here?
Can I move on to the next logic?
OK,
just move on to the next logic which is
we critical error check.
So here as part of ABC,
as part of Zone 2 design, if,
if there are any critical error records,
we do not load them into the target,
we wrote them to the error detail table.
If,
if there are any informational error
records, only informational error records,
we'll route them to both target table and
error trickle table.
Target table in the sense is just an
informational record, informational error,
right?
So we're routing them into the job rule
error detail table so that we can using
this record we can notify the admin team
later like other whoever it is intended
to be, we'll notify them later.
So that's the reason why we're routing to
both channels.
OK, so here next is critical error check.
So whatever record,
whatever columns that are marked as
critical.
So those only I have taken if any one of
this is null, then my critical check is Y,
we'll set is north.
Yeah, this is a critical error check.
I'm using this error check here.
If it is, if my critical check is N,
then my record will be.
If it is N, my record will be valid.
If it is Y then my record was will be
invalid.
Because if any one of this is null,
I'm marking the critical error check as Y
else it is Nash.
If it is N,
my record is valid else it is invalid.
OK source database name,
source schema name, table name,
source record identifier all these are
hardware values.
Like these three are completely hardware
values.
It depends upon your table details.
Just source details.
And here we are populating the UUID value
a source recorder identifier.
OK once this is done,
there is a router and output and output
groups.
So here we have error group and balance
reconciliation group, right?
These two,
these two need to be considered.
So here I'm populating invalid records.
That means critical error records or not
is not not is null of error description.
So in case of error description logic,
we are just populating,
we are populating even the informational
records, right?
That's the reason why in order to
populate even the informational records,
I'm just taking this in my condition.
OK, very good here.
Let's so after this,
we have created a a job rule,
error detail, temp table,
temp table and snowflake.
So we'll just map all the columns here,
job ID, execution, run ID, job run ID,
source, database name, source schema name,
source table name, source identifier,
error description, and the source.
These are audit columns,
so we'll map all these columns.
So here record level entries will be
enter will be puff will be will be made
into this job temp of snowflakes and from
that snowflake rows transform rows to
like this single row will be transposed
to multiple rows and those that will be
taken care in the job post loose exists.
OK, that's it.
This is how we have to do for DQ checks.
OK, Yeah, if we have are we good here?
Are we good on DQ check implementation?
As of now,
we are implementing everything in the ETL.
OK for DQ.
Does anyone have any question here?
No, Aishwarya, they are clear.
OK and then balance reconciliation group.
So here we are trying to perform the
balance source,
balance metric calculation.
We will be performing the metric
calculation,
source metric calculation only on the
valid records.
That means the records which are true
like the records which which which don't
have any critical error,
critical error issue and like no change
record whatever the records that are
rejected will not be considered on
balance reconciliation calculation.
And we are also not considering the RA
records here OK for source balance metric
calculation.
So once we get those records,
so like here,
we are trying to do a diction count of a
particular column.
So that's why this is very long.
Otherwise it will be very simple.
Directly we can use the aggregate
transformation.
We'll just group by using job run ID and
we'll do an aggregate.
So it's just like, it's just like if,
if we have any aggregator,
we just do a some of that column.
So if we have any amount column,
we'll just do a some of that amount
column.
If there are no records,
then we'll we'll have it as zero.
Like I'm just doing it like to handle
that null value OK for this particular.
For this particular distinct count we
have an additional transformation like
sorted wherein we are we will be getting
the getting only the only the columns
that are required.
So here I'm trying to do get the distinct
count of broker party identifier column
from the source.
So for this I'm just bringing source
party ID.
Rest all are just audit columns like all
these are ABC related columns and these
two are just audit columns which will
have same value for all the record.
So I'm using this column to perform
extinct like I'm like we're extinct.
We're doing a sort and in the advance I'm
we have given extinct so that extinct
will be performed on the using this
broker party address.
So this way we'll get this way,
we'll get only the distinct values of
source broker party ID.
And here in the aggregate transformation,
I'm just doing the count of that
particular source party 8, OK.
And then we'll have an expression
transformation here.
Whatever the values that we get,
we will try to congratulate all those
values.
So here we have only broker party ID.
This, this is the target column next, OK.
And the corresponding corresponding
source count value.
As we are having only one balance
translation check, we have this only one.
Otherwise we'll have it like this.
If we have multiple balancing metrics,
we'll just use our pipe symbol and we'll
have another a party amount mainly then
we'll have this management.
So it's basically it will have like we'll
have all the values separated by 5C.
Yeah, that's it.
And we will make,
we will perform this and we will,
we will like load it into our balance
reconciliation timetable.
It will have columns like job ID,
execution, run ID, job run ID,
source aggregate text and audit calls.
So source aggregate text is important
here.
So we'll just have all the balance,
source balance metric values within a
single text value.
And we,
we are populating it into this text.
OK, this is balance reconciliation part.
Does anyone have any question here?
OK,
let's move on to the next thing which is
job run stats stem.
So here we're directly routing the source
records into this flow.
We are not going after router here only
for error bound reckon we have created
groups and we have separate flows.
But whereas for job run stats we are
directly doing performing calculations on
the direct source columns which is
grouping by job run ID and in the
aggregate we are trying to get the source
record count and target reject.
Let me start get unchanged record forms.
So count of one will give you all the
source record form and the target
unchanged record form.
So within the logic within the source
query itself, we have a change flag.
If my change flag has as a value like no
change,
then my V unchanged flag will will be 1
otherwise it's zero.
So I'm just doing a sum of all the
columns to get the target.
Target unchanged report comes.
I'll just make an entry into this job run
stats timetable which is in snowflake
like this.
So it will have a column like job ID,
execution and a job run ID.
So super count,
target engine count and odd columns.
So all these are snowflake timetables.
Using these snowflake timetables we will
be loading the data there like the
entries from snowflake to actual rotor
tables.
In case of DQ we are having actual error
like normal error detail table in both
snowflake and Aurora database.
So both will acts like a same.
Both will hold the same data.
While we are making entries into Aurora
we all we will be making entries into the
snowflake error detail table.
OK, Apart from this,
all these timetables should be cleaned
using the job ID.
Job run stats, error, error detail,
timetable and balance reconciliation
table.
All this needs to be cleaned before
before the load OK using the oh Oh no not
for everything.
The the job runs OK in case of restart.
If we no I'll I'll get back on this using
just job ID.
All these tables should be cleaned OK
maybe this I have added as part of the
restart but we are handling it in in a
different way.
We are not in case of restart,
we are not get loading the stage table
itself.
So we don't need this.
We have just need to delete the records
for our job.
It it's just a timetable right way whose
details whose like job related details
are already in place in our actual order
ABC tables,
so we don't need the entrance in them can
delete.
I'll just update this logic.
OK,
if there is any like any other
information on this delete part,
I'll I'll I'll note I'll inform you.
But for now,
whatever the records that are related to
this particular job ID should be removed
from the temp snowflake tables.
OK if we are good on this test table
let's more let's more.
And also one more thing if your table
have error DQ checks then only implement
this job job job.
If your table has balance reconciliation
then only implement this flow otherwise
you can ignore.
You can just every table will have job
run stats time table.
But these two depends upon your
functionality of the table.
OK, OK.
We are implementing all the ABC stuff in
the main mapping in the sorry related to
our table in the source to stage load
mapping only.
OK, this is sorry.
Yeah, OK.
If this next,
it's next coming onto this main load
table, it's not having anything ABC,
it's just loading from stage to main road
mapping.
It again depends on the functionality.
OK, so once this main load is completed,
we have a job post loss access where
we'll have job role error,
detail load balance, reconciliation,
table load,
and the final update in the job role
execution log update and then job role
execution log.
Sorry,
job run starts final update based upon
the status and notification will be sent
out.
So if any of this task fails,
if the stage load fails,
this will be triggered.
This task flow will be triggered.
If this fails, this will be triggered.
OK,
this is just a job post load failure
failure subtask flow.
So it's just expecting these parameters.
OK, this is that's it.
I think we are good and notification of
the job will be handled here only.
I just want to show it at at a high level.
So this is job post load failure.
So if our source to stage or so stage 2
stage 2 main load.
If any of these loads fail during the
execution maybe due to some data issue or
any any issue due to some data issue
execution error basically then this this
will be trigger where we will just if we
if we have any DQ check.
So this is what I'm trying to say like
this is the DQ indicator we have to
provide it in the parameter file.
So if it is why then only this will be
performed.
So before for every job rule assignment
there will be an entry into this job re
execution log table and after the load
the status and corresponding log will be
updated in this table.
OK, if my stage load gets failed,
whatever the entries that are made into
this table as part of my job reload
should be updated to fail and the
corresponding error message should be
populated.
So for that purpose I'm I have to update
the entries.
I have used this task to update it.
If this execution fails there will be a
notification sign out and it will throw
an error and after that we have job post
load, Job run starts post load failure.
Whatever the entry that is made into the
job run starts table before during the
preload will be updated to fail in this
table and also it will make an entry into
the job error log error stress table.
So it's just like a error error log table
for every job failure.
Like for any job failure we are making an
entry into this table.
OK have this failed.
It's just a notification ask if this if
it's execution it's with it.
Once we are updating the statuses in into
these two tables to fail,
we are sending out that this particular
job load has failed.
OK job load of this and we are also
adding job name, job ID, job and ID.
OK this is failed like the we are sending
out a failure notification at the job
level.
If it is successful the notification is
taken care in the task flow in this job
post the task law.
So what it is doing it will just load the
our records from RA time to RME
Referential integrated report and then it
will load records from job rule error
details claim to actual job rule error
details and then it will update the
entries in the job rule execution log
table.
And so these two will be performed only
when the decision indicator is Y like
sorry dictate check indicator is Y.
And after that it will check for the
amount the balance check indicator or
count threshold indicator.
If any one of this is Y,
then only it will perform the balance
reconciliation step.
Otherwise it won't perform.
It will it will get it will be skipped OK
and OK.
If OK once after this balance
reconciliation,
we have job run stress update.
After that we will send out a
notification based upon the status.
So there is a like there are some
parameters we like.
Result parameters I have already like
have the logic within the job branch set
post load,
post load success mapping itself.
So I'm using all the subjects and results
to frame this notification.
Whatever the status is,
it will frame everything and it will send
out the notification.
If it is success, warning,
failure it will send out and here it will
check my actual job job status.
If it is failed then it will it will fail
this task as it else it will go to end.
So here I'm having some additional tasks
right?
So if any of these executions,
any of these components execution failed
in the middle,
it will just update the statuses and send
out sends out a notification and throw
this is just trying the OK,
I'll it is going to this step.
OK, this is going to this step.
So here it it is again sending out a
notification.
So in case of any failure,
we are trying to send out a notification,
any execution failure at any step that's
it.
Yeah, I think we are good.
This is this is what you have.
We have to implement like ABC integrate.
We have to integrate ABC on our actual
table load.
Let me know if anyone has any question on
this end to end flow.